# **Austin Hartline**

https://euclideansphere.github.io

### **OBJECTIVE**

Proven engineer with 7+ years FTE experience seeking senior backend focused SWE role with opportunity to mentor, be mentored, and think critically about how to best empower decision makers with the data they need to be successful.

### **EDUCATION**

## Milwaukee School of Engineering

Milwaukee, WI

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering; GPA: 3.8

Sep. 2013 - May. 2017

Email: austin.dev@protonmail.com

Mobile:  $+1\ 414-334-4061$ 

• Eagle Scout; BSA

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages: SQL, Ruby, Typescript, C#, Terraform, Python

• Technologies: PostgreSQL, ReactJS, Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, AWS

#### Experience

## Software Contracting, Self Employment

(Remote) Milwaukee, WI

Jul 2023 - Present

Software Contractor

- Rapid Delivery: Prototype, build, and iterate on key features with tight deadlines to win customers and obtain Series A funding for a CMMS startup (NodaFi).
- Javascript, Node: Build full stack features for a React-Native mobile app and a React web app backed by a GraphQL NestJS (NodeJS) web API.
- **Performance**: Instrument DataDog telemetry and use MariaDB (MySQL) query planner to troubleshoot and improve critical page performance.

### Betterment, Inc

(Remote) New York, NY

Full Stack Engineer III

Jan 2022 - Jun 2023 (layoff)

- Ruby on Rails: Design and build Ruby on Rails REST APIs, collaborating with mobile development while planning for concurrent ReactJS and StimulusJS web consumers.
- Data Engineering: Lead data engineering financial audit project orchestrated with Airflow, DBT (ETL and job definition solution) against an AWS Redshift Data Warehouse to provide required proofs to regulators.
- Mentorship, Leadership: Mentor junior developer on temporal SQL query optimization, data modeling, estimation, and negotiating project scope to foster IC growth.
- **Testing**: Ensure software behavioral correctness using Jest, RSpec, DBT test, and in-house open-source software testing solutions to prevent escaped defects.
- **Design**: Write technical design proposal to build organizational consensus around novel account access mechanisms to allow implementation of recurring transfers.
- **Javascript**: Became a designated organization wide Javascript Platform Reviewer to provide technical support to peers and influence company web frontend standards.
- On Call Responsibility: Participate in team and organization on-call processes, handling customer tickets and coordinating support for live production outages.

### GenoPalate, Inc

(Remote) Milwaukee, WI

Software Engineer (Mid-Senior Level)

Sep 2020 - Jan 2022

- Javascript, Node: Collaborate with a small team to estimate, scope, and build features for a React-Native mobile application and a React web frontend backed by an ExpressJS / Knex (NodeJS) web service.
- Integration: Communicate with external vendors to design and implement DNA data integrations, automating all manual process from shipment to DNA sample processing and DNA sequence ingestion.
- Influence Team: Advocate for, plan, and lead effort to standardize testing (Jest), implement type checking (Typescript), code review, deployment, and error monitoring (Sentry) to reduce escaped defect rate by 90%.
- Agile: Participate in Agile / SCRUM process, including collaborative design sessions with stakeholders, iterative delivery, team estimations, and building consensus.

- Node and PostgreSQL: Own and fix complex technical issues with RDBMS Node runtime and data corruption to eliminate production outages.
- PostgreSQL: Draft written plan and execute project to upgrade AWS RDS PostgreSQL instance without any unplanned downtime.
- o Shopify Integration: Build robust fault tolerant support for Shopify order integration in Node / Typscript on AWS (ECS, Lambda, SQS, S3) to ingest every customer purchase.
- o Cloud Infrastructure / DevOps: Pitch, plan, and lead project to standardize all AWS infrastructure deployment and CI/CD through Github Actions, Terraform (IaC), and Docker to eliminate clickops deployment error.

Travel Break Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

Wantable

Milwaukee, WI

Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2019 - May 2020

- React, Typescript: Assist lead UX designer in building a Typescript, React, and SCSS design system to replace CSS style guide to create a coherent automatable UX.
- o Data Science: Integrate rich Python / R data science models into dynamic React / Rails UIs to enable internal users to make quantitatively smarter decisions.
- Project Ownership: Prototype, and iteratively deliver customer facing e-commerce solutions using Rails, Redis, PostgreSQL and AngularJS to sell more product.
- Warehouse Management: Build and improve warehouse logistics and inventory management solutions in .NET and Ruby on Rails to reduce labor inefficiency.
- Data Integration: Build and optimize Rails (ARel) and PostgreSQL export jobs to marketing channels to reduce cloud compute costs by \$2,000/month and improve customer acquisition, churn, and lifetime value metrics.
- o Performance Monitoring: Use New Relic, Sentry, and Lighthouse to improve user facing page and image load performance, which improved SEO and sales metrics.

Direct Supply, Inc. Milwaukee, WI

Sotware Engineer May 2017 - Feb 2019

- .NET Development: Develop features and integrations for a catalog based food and equipment ecommerce solution in the eldercare industry using C#, Razor, Typescript, ReactJS, CoffeeScript, AngularJS.
- Domain Driven Development: Demonstrate strong understanding of CAP theorum and distributed computing by designing and building fault tolerant integrations between disjointed lines of business and domains.
- Microservices: Collaborate with team to design and build 12 factor microservices in C#, SQL Server, and documented with OpenAPI to automate quote generation and work order tasks.
- o Microservice Cloud Infrastructure: Lead setup of automated infrastructure deployment to AWS ECS Fargate / AWS RDS (SQL Server) using Terraform, Hashicorp Vault, Bash, Docker, and Gitlab Pipelines.
- Terraform: Pioneer IaC implementation (Terraform) and educate several teams of engineers how to deploy to multiply org efficiency.
- Open Source Contribution: Identify and fix defects in Terraform AWS Provider (golang) to improve deploy idempotency.
- Event Driven Architecture: Use AWS Lambda, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ to connect distributed systems and automate services procurement.
- Mentorship: Mentor intern and junior developers to increase team velocity and foster team strength.
- LEAN UX User Testing: Use LEAN UX methodology to perform direct user research with prototypes and A/B testing to reduce feature risk and improve delivery confidence.

### Direct Supply, Inc

Milwaukee, WI

Sotware Engineer (Intern)

Jan 2014 - May 2017

- RabbitMQ: Integrate RabbitMQ event broker to satisfy user needs across lines of business.
- .NET Modernization: Participate in an agile team (full time as of 2016) to modernize 100s of legacy jobs and distributed web systems to a modern .NET on AWS cloud based architecture.
- SQL: Investigate and fix high I/O SQL deadlocking issues, with over 1000 transactions per second.